<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nmap on Technical Notes</title>
    <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/nmap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nmap on Technical Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015 - 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/nmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nmap top 1000 ports</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/nmap-top-1000-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/nmap-top-1000-ports/</guid>
      <description>In the  Nmap Network Scanning  book, chapter 15 , section  Port Specification and Scan Order , to quote &amp;ldquo;By default, Nmap scans the most common 1,000 ports for each protocol.&amp;rdquo; [1]
However, the documentation did not mention the list of 1000 ports.
So, how to identify and show those 1000 ports ?
--top-ports n: the n highest-ratio ports found in nmap-services. n must be 1 or greater -v: verbose level, to print the -oG: grepable output - : output to stdout $ nmap --top-ports 1000 -v -oG - localhost Note: refer to /usr/share/nmap/nmap-services file for the service name and protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate port scanning with Nmap &amp; Ndiff</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/automate-port-scanning-with-nmap-ndiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/automate-port-scanning-with-nmap-ndiff/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Nmap Ndiff  Scan and interpret the results/diffs   Automation     Nmap Ndiff Ndiff is a tool to aid in the comparison of Nmap scans. Ndiff, like the standard diff utility, compares two scans at a time. It takes two Nmap XML output files and prints the differences between them. The differences observed are:
 Host states (e.g. up to down) Port states (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan the Internet with Nmap</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-nmap/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Scan a Network/Subnet  Host Discovery Scan a large public network Scan a private network: 192.168.1.0/24   Scan a Single Target Remote OS and Service Detection  Host and Port State Reason   List of Examples     Scan a Network/Subnet Host Discovery HOST DISCOVERY: -sL: List Scan - simply list targets to scan, without sending any packets to the target hosts, useful to generate list of target hosts and dns resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traceroute, Firewalls &amp; Geo-IP</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/traceroute-firewalls-geoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/traceroute-firewalls-geoip/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Traceroute  ICMP mode UDP mode TCP mode Output format explanation   Hping3 InTrace Nmap: traceroute-geolocation script    Traceroute Traceroute is useful for diagnosing networking problems, e.g., end-to-end connectivty, complement with ping. It can also be used to pinpoint the location of devices, routers and firewalls. The tracerouting tools fundamentally rely on the IP packet&amp;rsquo;s field - TTL (Time-To-Live, decremented at each hop, dies at 0), they send short-life IP packets and wait for Time Exceeded ICMP packets reporting the death of these packets from a router, consequently reveal the route.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
