<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>traceroute on Technical Notes</title>
    <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/traceroute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in traceroute on Technical Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015 - 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/traceroute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Traceroute</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/dynamic-traceroute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/dynamic-traceroute/</guid>
      <description>mtr Often times, troublesome networks won&amp;rsquo;t show up in the results of a few packets. mtr combines the functionality of the traceroute and ping utils and enables user to constantly poll a remote server to see the latency and performance changes over time. It&amp;rsquo;s not installed by default on most linux systems, simply get it from the distribution and package manager of choice:
$ sudo apt-get install mtr To debug remotely over ssh where no GUI is available, use the --curses or -t option:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Traceroute</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/reading-traceroute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/reading-traceroute/</guid>
      <description>This post extends the discussion on traceroute in previous post Traceroute, Firewalls &amp;amp; Geo-IP, and focused on intepreting the traceroute report.
Output format explanation:  v--- the router/ip-addr traversed by the packet [Hop] [Hostname/(IP-addr)] [RTT1] [RTT2] [RTT3] ^--- transit no. of the route ^---- round-trip time The round-trip time (RTT) is the latency (delay between sending the packet and getting the response).
By default, traceroute sends 3 packets per TTL increment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traceroute, Firewalls &amp; Geo-IP</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/traceroute-firewalls-geoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/traceroute-firewalls-geoip/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Traceroute  ICMP mode UDP mode TCP mode Output format explanation   Hping3 InTrace Nmap: traceroute-geolocation script    Traceroute Traceroute is useful for diagnosing networking problems, e.g., end-to-end connectivty, complement with ping. It can also be used to pinpoint the location of devices, routers and firewalls. The tracerouting tools fundamentally rely on the IP packet&amp;rsquo;s field - TTL (Time-To-Live, decremented at each hop, dies at 0), they send short-life IP packets and wait for Time Exceeded ICMP packets reporting the death of these packets from a router, consequently reveal the route.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
