<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>port-scanning on Technical Notes</title>
    <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/port-scanning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in port-scanning on Technical Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015 - 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/port-scanning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scan a network for vulnerabilities with Nessus</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-a-network-for-vulnerabilities-with-nessus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-a-network-for-vulnerabilities-with-nessus/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Scan a network  Advanced Scans Basic Network Scans Launch A Scan   Results Exports  Executive Report Technical Report       Scan a network Target: 192.168.1.0/24 Nessus provides a set of ready-to-use templates. For general scans, the (1) Advanced Scan and (2) Basic Network Scan would work. The differences are the Advanced Scan supports the Compliance and Plugins which can be used to fine-tune the compliance checks (credentials are required) and plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan the Internet with Masscan</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-masscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-masscan/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Scan large IP block Exclude IP blocks of sensitive part of the Internet Include IP blocks for targeted IP blocks Transmission Rates Specify ports and ranges Pull the services and banners Output formats Manage config for different scanning strategies     The base system used to perform the scans:
root@192.168.1.11:~# uname -a Linux kali 4.9.0-kali3-amd64 #1 SMP Debian 4.9.13-1kali2 (2017-03-07) x86_64 GNU/Linux Scan large IP block Scan the entire 175.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port-knocking</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/port-knocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/port-knocking/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Enabling knockd Port-knocking  Open the port Close the port   Using Hping3 / Nmap  Open the port Close the port   Alternatives     Introduction Port-knocking is a stealth method to open ports that the firewall keeps closed by default. A port-knock server listens to all traffic on an ethernet (or PPP) interface, looking for a special &amp;ldquo;knock&amp;rdquo; sequences of port-hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nmap top 1000 ports</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/nmap-top-1000-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/nmap-top-1000-ports/</guid>
      <description>In the  Nmap Network Scanning  book, chapter 15 , section  Port Specification and Scan Order , to quote &amp;ldquo;By default, Nmap scans the most common 1,000 ports for each protocol.&amp;rdquo; [1]
However, the documentation did not mention the list of 1000 ports.
So, how to identify and show those 1000 ports ?
--top-ports n: the n highest-ratio ports found in nmap-services. n must be 1 or greater -v: verbose level, to print the -oG: grepable output - : output to stdout $ nmap --top-ports 1000 -v -oG - localhost Note: refer to /usr/share/nmap/nmap-services file for the service name and protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate port scanning with Nmap &amp; Ndiff</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/automate-port-scanning-with-nmap-ndiff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/automate-port-scanning-with-nmap-ndiff/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Nmap Ndiff  Scan and interpret the results/diffs   Automation     Nmap Ndiff Ndiff is a tool to aid in the comparison of Nmap scans. Ndiff, like the standard diff utility, compares two scans at a time. It takes two Nmap XML output files and prints the differences between them. The differences observed are:
 Host states (e.g. up to down) Port states (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan the Internet with Nmap</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/scan-the-internet-with-nmap/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Scan a Network/Subnet  Host Discovery Scan a large public network Scan a private network: 192.168.1.0/24   Scan a Single Target Remote OS and Service Detection  Host and Port State Reason   List of Examples     Scan a Network/Subnet Host Discovery HOST DISCOVERY: -sL: List Scan - simply list targets to scan, without sending any packets to the target hosts, useful to generate list of target hosts and dns resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hping3: Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/hping3-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/hping3-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  hping3 and the firewall  ICMP mode TCP mode UDP mode SCAN mode      hping3 and the firewall Mode default mode TCP -0 --rawip RAW IP mode -1 --icmp ICMP mode -2 --udp UDP mode -8 --scan SCAN mode. Example: hping --scan 1-30,70-90 -S www.target.host -9 --listen listen mode ICMP mode The typical ping utility and the hping3 equivalent, sending ICMP-echo and receiving ICMP-reply:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
