<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>packet-analysis on Technical Notes</title>
    <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/packet-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in packet-analysis on Technical Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2015 - 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tzyluen.github.io/tags/packet-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deep packet inspection</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/deep-packet-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/deep-packet-inspection/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction nDPI  Build and install ndpi-netfilter   Realtime capture Iptables/netfilter  SSH Youtube Social Networks       Introduction Port-independent, P2P, and encrypted protocols and packets have made the conventional network traffics analysis that based on packet header (transport protocol and application ports) obsolete. Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology can be used to identify and classify these encrypted, port-independent, P2P protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL injection with sqlmap</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/sql-injection-with-sqlmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/sql-injection-with-sqlmap/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Scan for vulnerability  Create a HTTP request file Scan the target   Explore the vulnerable target&amp;rsquo;s databases and system  Dictionary attack against password hashes and dump full credentials OS Shell Access Behind the scene Speedup the process and specify custom injection payloads   Capture and decode the payload  with Ngrep with Wireshark Decode the payload       Scan for vulnerability Create a HTTP request file   Use -r option instead of passing long parameters of --url, --user-agent, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireshark: A quick troubleshoot on slow network (1)</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/wireshark-a-quick-troubleshoot-on-slow-network-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/wireshark-a-quick-troubleshoot-on-slow-network-1/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Quick drill into errors and connection issues Identify the protocols with high traffic Get the connection speed to a site Get the time spent in waiting for a response Identify the bad packets (TCP errors) ratio    Generate the statistic:- runs wireshark and starts capturing the network packets until the statistic builds.
 Quick drill into errors and connection issues   Navigates to &amp;#39;Analyze&amp;#39; → &amp;#39;Expert Info&amp;#39; , a high number of errors and warnings indicates problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ngrep: quick peek at http traffic</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/ngrep-quick-peek-at-http-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/ngrep-quick-peek-at-http-traffic/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Quick peek Sorts out unique User-Agent (devices) Monitor the occurrence of the keywords Monitor HTTP GET | POST traffic by IP addresses DNS     Quick peek Monitor activities on device eth0 port 80:
-W byline: linefeeds (LF) are printed as linefeeds, more readable.
-qt: quiet mode and print human-readable timestamp.
# ngrep -d eth0 -W byline -qt port 80  Sorts out unique User-Agent (devices) In corporate environment, desktop/laptop OS build is often standardized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract files from captured network traffic pcap (2)</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/extract-files-from-captured-network-traffic-pcap-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/extract-files-from-captured-network-traffic-pcap-2/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Tcpxtract Tcpextract     Tcpxtract  Supports 26 file formats, extensible (/etc/tcpxtract.conf), however it requires the clear start and end markers. Supports only TCP packets, no UDP.    Live capture from an interface and extract:
$ mkdir -p /tmp/enp0s3-tcpxtract-output $ sudo tcpxtract -d enp0s3 -o /tmp/enp0s3-tcpxtract-output   Extract from the pcap file:
   Tcpextract   Similar to both tcpflow and tcpxtract, tcpextract extracts all files it recognized from a pcap file or interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract files from captured network traffic pcap (1)</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/extract-files-from-captured-network-traffic-pcap-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/extract-files-from-captured-network-traffic-pcap-1/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Wireshark  HTTP objects and files Binary files   Tcpflow &amp;amp; Foremost     Introduction The process is mostly the same in network packets data-carving, which comprises of:
 Gain access and collect the raw bytes Strip the protocol information Extract and write the data to file  The differences of these tools are their capabilities i.e., the supported protocols and file formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sniff DNS Queries</title>
      <link>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/sniff-dns-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tzyluen.github.io/post/sniff-dns-queries/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Dnstop Tcpdump Wireshark / Tshark     Dnstop is a console libpcap application that displays various tables of DNS traffic on a network including:
 Source IP addresses Destination IP addresses Query types Top level domains Second level domains  # dnstop enp0s3 -l 3  Use ctrl-r to reset the counter/refresh the history to get the latest queries.
  Tcpdump Capture packets from port 53 (DNS):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
